{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Biologist who discovered penicillin.","incorrectAnswers":["Renaissance mathematician and astronomer who believed Sun was the centre of the Universe - rather than Earth.","United most of Western Europe to form the Carolingian Empire.","Roman ruler who oversaw the demise of the Roman Republic to be replaced with a Roman Emperor."],"question":"Which of the following describes Alexander Fleming?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"United States of America","incorrectAnswers":["Australia","New Zealand","Ireland"],"question":"Washington, D.C. is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Penne","incorrectAnswers":["Ravioli","Fusilli","Orecchiette"],"question":"Which pasta's name means 'Pens'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Arthur Conan Doyle","incorrectAnswers":["Agatha Christie","Oscar Wilde","George Orwell"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Hound of the Baskervilles'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Barack Obama","incorrectAnswers":["Calvin Coolidge","Ronald Reagan","Zachary Taylor"],"question":"Who was the 44th president of the USA, in term during the period 2009–2017?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Cleveland Indians","incorrectAnswers":["Cleveland Celtics","Cleveland Hornets","Cleveland Blackhawks"],"question":"Which of these is a baseball team based in Cleveland?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Ljubljana","incorrectAnswers":["Prague","Leipzig","Berlin"],"question":"Which of these cities is in Slovenia?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Joe Pesci","incorrectAnswers":["John Belushi","Robert De Niro","Al Pacino"],"question":"The two crooks in the 1990 film 'Home Alone'', one was played by Daniel Stern, who was the other?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Metallica","incorrectAnswers":["Alice Cooper","The Pussycat Dolls","Three 6 Mafia"],"question":"Which American heavy metal band released the studio album 'ReLoad'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"A man investigates the disappearance of a murderer who escaped from a hospital for the insane.","incorrectAnswers":["When two girls move to the country, they have adventures with the forest spirits who live nearby.","Two bounty hunters with the same intentions team up to track down an escaped Mexican outlaw.","The son of a city's mastermind falls in love with a working-class prophet."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie Shutter Island?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Ethiopia","incorrectAnswers":["Tunisia","South Africa","Democratic Republic of the Congo"],"question":"Addis Ababa is a city in which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Beatles","incorrectAnswers":["The Rolling Stones","Oasis","Simon & Garfunkel"],"question":"Which band did Paul McCartney belong to?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"War Of The Worlds","incorrectAnswers":["The Archers","Johnny Got His Gun","Moon Over Morocco"],"question":"What pre-tv radio show caused hysteria when it was first aired?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"William Pitt","incorrectAnswers":["Anthony Eden","Margaret Thatcher","Clement Attlee"],"question":"Who Was The Youngest British Prime Minister?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Fawn","incorrectAnswers":["A Joey","A Spiderling","A Farrow"],"question":"A young deer is known as what?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Lancelot","incorrectAnswers":["Galahad","Tristan","Percival"],"question":"According to Arthurian legend, which knight had an affair with Queen Guinevere, the wife of King Arthur?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"12","incorrectAnswers":["11","10","9"],"question":"According To The Christmas Song, How Many Drummers Drumming Were There?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Argentina","incorrectAnswers":["Trinidad and Tobago","Chile","Grenada"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Brazil?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Pomegranate ","incorrectAnswers":["Mango","Cranberry","Raspberry"],"question":"From Which Fruit Is Grenadine Obtained?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"3","incorrectAnswers":["1","0","2"],"question":"How many hearts does an octopus have?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Hob","incorrectAnswers":["A Tiercel","A Stallion","A Billy"],"question":"What is a male ferret known as?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Taiwan","incorrectAnswers":["Japan","Sri Lanka","Myanmar"],"question":"Where would you find the city of Kaohsiung?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Jimi Hendrix Experience","incorrectAnswers":["Poison","The Pussycat Dolls","Three 6 Mafia"],"question":"Which English-American psychedelic rock band released the album 'Are You Experienced'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Tempura ","incorrectAnswers":["Bento","Sashimi","Nori"],"question":"What name is given to the Japanese dish in which fish, shellfish, or vegetables are fried in batter?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"A paleontologist is tasked with protecting two children when cloned dinosaurs are set free.","incorrectAnswers":["During WWII a Jewish waiter uses humor to protect his son from the realities of war.","A maverick teacher emboldens his students to new heights of self-expression.","A car salesman's inept crime falls apart due to his and his henchmen's bungling."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie Jurassic Park?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Africa","incorrectAnswers":["South America","Oceania","Europe"],"question":"The country of São Tomé and Príncipe is on which continent?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Maafe","incorrectAnswers":["Pozole","Enchilada","Tamales"],"question":"Which is these is not a Mexican dish?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Indonesia","incorrectAnswers":["Bangladesh","Thailand","Mongolia"],"question":"Jakarta is a city in which country?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Iran","incorrectAnswers":["Turkey","Thailand","Northern Ireland"],"question":"In which country would you find the UNESCO World Heritage site of The Bam Citadel?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Mark Rothko","incorrectAnswers":["James Abbott McNeill Whistler","Vincent van Gogh","Henri Rousseau"],"question":"Which artist painted \"Royal Red and Blue\"","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Trafalgar","incorrectAnswers":["Waterloo","Hastings","Bosworth Field"],"question":"21 October 1805 Is The Date Of Which Famous Battle?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Touch base","incorrectAnswers":["Home run","Out of left field","Grand slam"],"question":"Which expression, originating from baseball, means to keep someone informed briefly?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Six","incorrectAnswers":["Seven","Yellow","Two"],"question":"What does the word 'seis' mean in Spanish?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"The Neverending Story","incorrectAnswers":["Mio, My Son","The Adventures of Tom Sawyer","The Alchemist"],"question":"In which book does the character 'Bastian Balthazar Bux' appear?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Nepal","incorrectAnswers":["Sudan","Myanmar","Tanzania"],"question":"Kathmandu is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Hiroshima","incorrectAnswers":["Jericho","Babel","Dresden"],"question":"What city was destroyed by a 'little boy'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Kevin Costner","incorrectAnswers":["Dwayne Johnson","Shah Rukh Khan","Gérard Depardieu"],"question":"Which actor has had roles in films including Batman v Superman: Dawn of Justice and The Untouchables?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Oceania","incorrectAnswers":["South America","Europe","Asia"],"question":"The country of Marshall Islands is on which continent?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"signs","incorrectAnswers":["is concerned with earth materials that can be utilized for economic and/or industrial purposes","the practice of escaping from restraints or other traps","a branch of logic focusing on part-whole relationships"],"question":"What is Semiology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Jurassic","incorrectAnswers":["Triassic","Cretaceous","Devonian"],"question":"In which time period did the diplodocus live?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Green Day","incorrectAnswers":["Red Hot Chili Peppers","Nirvana","Metallica"],"question":"Which musical group consists of Tre Cool and Mike Dirnt, among others?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Spanish","incorrectAnswers":["Portuguese","Mexican","Andorran"],"question":"What is the nationality of Picasso?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Creedence Clearwater Revival","incorrectAnswers":["MercyMe","The Pussycat Dolls","Three 6 Mafia"],"question":"Which American roots rock band released the studio album 'Cosmo's Factory'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Catharine of Aragon","incorrectAnswers":["Anne Boleyn","Jane Seymour","Mary, Queen of Scots "],"question":"Who did King Henry VIII marry when he was 18?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Oyster ","incorrectAnswers":["Shrimp","Lobster","Clam"],"question":"Apparently resembling a marine creature, which morsel of meat found in a fowl's back is reckoned by some to be the tastiest?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"India","incorrectAnswers":["Tajikistan","Kyrgyzstan","Uzbekistan"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Pakistan?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Departed","incorrectAnswers":["Double Indemnity","Indiana Jones and the Last Crusade","Groundhog Day"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'An undercover cop and a mole in the police try to identify each other while infiltrating a gang.'","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Winnie the Pooh","incorrectAnswers":["Piglet","Tigger","Eeyore"],"question":"What is the name of the bear in the collection of stories by A. A. Milne?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Belgium","incorrectAnswers":["Liechtenstein","Slovenia","San Marino"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Germany?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Titanic","incorrectAnswers":["Romeo + Juliet","The Beach","The Great Gatsby"],"question":"In which iconic '90s film did Leonardo DiCaprio play the role of Jack Dawson?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1939","incorrectAnswers":["1941","1945","1937"],"question":"What year did World War II begin?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"U2","incorrectAnswers":["Public Image Ltd.","The Script","The Cure"],"question":"Which Irish rock band released the studio album 'Achtung Baby'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Mason","incorrectAnswers":["Carpenter","Electrician","Plumber"],"question":"Which expert should you call if you're building with stone?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Roast Beef Dinner","incorrectAnswers":["Stamppot","Chicken Machboos","Poutine"],"question":"Which of these dishes is most associated with England?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"South Korea","incorrectAnswers":["North Korea","Japan","Philippines"],"question":"Seoul is the capital of which country?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Canada","incorrectAnswers":["United States","United Kingdom","Australia"],"question":"Which country had its first female prime minister, Kim Campbell, serve in 1993?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Honiara","incorrectAnswers":["Conakry","Brazzaville","Port Vila"],"question":"What is the capital city of Solomon Islands?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Borscht","incorrectAnswers":["Stroganoff","Pelmeni","Blintz"],"question":"What is the name of the Russian beet soup usually served with sour cream?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"A bagel","incorrectAnswers":["A croissant","A muffin","A doughnut"],"question":"What breakfast item takes its name from the Yiddish word for 'ring' or 'bracelet'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Buck","incorrectAnswers":["A Bull","A Hob","A Ram"],"question":"What would you call a male squirrel?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Spiro Agnew","incorrectAnswers":["Richard Nixon","Gerald Ford","Lyndon B. Johnson"],"question":"Who resigned from the vice presidency and admitted tax evasion in 1967?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Aqua","incorrectAnswers":["Nena","Frankie Goes to Hollywood","OMC"],"question":"'Barbie Girl' was a one hit wonder in 1997 by which artist?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Parcel","incorrectAnswers":["Postal","Pound","Pouch"],"question":"What is the \"P\" in UPS, the world's largest package delivery company?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Daily Bugle","incorrectAnswers":["The Daily Planet","The New York Times","The Gotham Gazette"],"question":"Before becoming Spider-Man, Peter Parker worked as a photographer for which newspaper?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"William Shakespeare","incorrectAnswers":["Arthur C. Clarke","Isaac Newton","Enid Blyton"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Hamlet'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Michael Jackson","incorrectAnswers":["Prince","Madonna","Jamiroquai"],"question":"In 1993, which famous singer co-patented a pair of shoes that provided a \"Method and means for creating anti-gravity illusion\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Central Asia","incorrectAnswers":["Southeast Asia","North America","Africa"],"question":"From which part of the world do apples originate?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Lamborghini","incorrectAnswers":["Linux","Hermès","Tripadvisor"],"question":"Which of these brands has a bull on its logo?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Germany","incorrectAnswers":["France","Austria","Poland"],"question":"The medieval-style castle of Neuschwanstein is located in which country?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Lager ","incorrectAnswers":["Pilsner","Weiss","Helles"],"question":"Which alcoholic beverage's name is German for 'to store'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"George R. R. Martin","incorrectAnswers":["Stephen King","Jack Vance","Edgar Rice Burroughs"],"question":"Which author wrote 'A Storm of Swords'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1683","incorrectAnswers":["1453","1916","1189"],"question":"When did the Ottoman Empire reach its greatest territorial extent?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Cow","incorrectAnswers":["A Pen","A Sow","A Hen"],"question":"A female sea lion is known as what?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Two magicians in 1890s London engage in a battle to create the ultimate illusion.","incorrectAnswers":["An insurance representative lets a housewife seduce him into a scheme of insurance fraud and murder.","A stand-up comedian embarks on a downward spiral that leads to the creation of an iconic villain.","The life of a boxer whose temper led him to the top in the ring, but destroyed his life outside of it."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie The Prestige?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Trapezoid","incorrectAnswers":["Parallelogram","Rhombus","Rectangle"],"question":"What is the name of a shape with four sides of unequal length?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Anthony Hopkins","incorrectAnswers":["Jon Favreau","Benedict Cumberbatch","Robert Redford"],"question":"Which actor plays the role of Odin in the Marvel Cinematic Universe?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Pennsylvania Avenue","incorrectAnswers":["Broadway","Fifth Avenue","Star Walk"],"question":"What is the name of the street that runs from the White House to the Capitol and is used for ceremonial parades?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Cockfighting","incorrectAnswers":["Rugby","Horse Racing","Tennis"],"question":"In what sport did the word 'crestfallen' originate?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"25","incorrectAnswers":["21","19","30"],"question":"What is the name of the album by Adele that features the songs 'Hello' and 'When We Were Young'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"the immune system","incorrectAnswers":["living tissues","eggs","the laws and phenomena of aqueous vapors"],"question":"What is Immunology the study of?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Art deco","incorrectAnswers":["Cubism","Surrealism","Dadaism"],"question":"Which design style prevalent during the 1920s and 1930s was characterized by a sleek use of straight lines and slender forms?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Amsterdam","incorrectAnswers":["Rome","Düsseldorf","Zürich"],"question":"Which of these cities is in Netherlands?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Germany","incorrectAnswers":["Korea","Vietnam","Ireland"],"question":"Which country was split into two zones by the Yalta agreement?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Kurt Russell","incorrectAnswers":["Mark Ruffalo","Chiwetel Ejiofor","Mickey Rourke"],"question":"Which actor plays the role of Ego in the Marvel Cinematic Universe?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Little Men","incorrectAnswers":["Grown Women","Old Women","Out in the Barlows"],"question":"What was the sequel to Louisa May Alcott's \"Little Women\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Sodium Hydroxide","incorrectAnswers":["Potassium Sulfate","Nitrogen Chloride","Carbon Iodine"],"question":"Which substance has the chemical formula NaOH?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Minsk","incorrectAnswers":["Budapest","Vienna","Vaduz"],"question":"What is the capital city of Belarus?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"The Chronicles of Narnia","incorrectAnswers":["Harry Potter","Twilight","His Dark Materials"],"question":"In which book series does the character 'Edmund Pevensie' appear?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Beatles","incorrectAnswers":["Status Quo","Led Zeppelin","The Kings"],"question":"Which English rock band released the album 'A Hard Day's Night'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Bundt cake","incorrectAnswers":["Angel cake","Pound cake","Sponge cake"],"question":"What is the name of the trademarked ring-shaped cake baked in a tube pan with fluted sides?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Depeche Mode","incorrectAnswers":["Level 42","Dead or Alive","Radiohead"],"question":"Which English band released the album 'Black Celebration'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Percussion","incorrectAnswers":["Brass","Stringed","Woodwind"],"question":"What type of instrument is a bongo?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"France","incorrectAnswers":["Spain","Switzerland","Italy"],"question":"Paris is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Yellowstone","incorrectAnswers":["Yosemite","Grand Canyon","Mount Rushmore"],"question":"What national park is famous for its Old Faithful Geyser?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"The cerebellum","incorrectAnswers":["The amygdala","The hippocampus","The thalamus"],"question":"Which part of the brain is involved in the coordination of voluntary motor movements?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Hamlet","incorrectAnswers":["Polonius","Laertes","Ophelia"],"question":"What is the name of the character who utters the famous line 'To be, or not to be' in 'Hamlet'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Dead","incorrectAnswers":["Living","Undead","Corpse"],"question":"Which word is the last word in the titles of six of George Romero's zombie movies?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Juliett","incorrectAnswers":["Jump","Jericho","Jolly"],"question":"What word is used in the NATO Phonetic Alphabet for the letter J?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"John Adams","incorrectAnswers":["George Washington","Abraham Lincoln","Thomas Jefferson"],"question":"Who Was The First US President To Take Up Residence In The Whitehouse?","difficulty":"hard"},